<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>127.0.0.1 (Posts about Ideas)</title><link>https://0xfe11.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://0xfe11.github.io/categories/cat_ideas.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:zihe.goh@gmail.com"&gt;0xfe11&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 08:12:52 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Choices - An idea for a new game</title><link>https://0xfe11.github.io/posts/choices-an-idea-for-a-new-game/</link><dc:creator>0xfe11</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been a while since my last blog post. The other day, I suddenly had an idea that struck me and I thought I would like to
turn this idea into a game. So the game I want to make next is this. It is bascially a game about making choices and how sometimes
we do not obey the choices we make. I was thinking about how people always go back on their words when they promise to something
and I thought why not make a game about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea of the game is simple, it will start with a yes/no choice question. For example, do you like candies? If the player
answers yes, I will present a scenario that player will have to throw the candies away rather than keeping them and likewise for the
other choice. This way, when the game ends, I will show remind the player that the (original) choice they had make and the (actual) choice
that they executed is different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just want to show people that people usually promise things and not follow through. We are always fickle minded and we don't always
know what we want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would be the game idea for now. Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://0xfe11.github.io/posts/choices-an-idea-for-a-new-game/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 03:44:57 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>